Guide to the Pennsylvania Peace Links Records, 1978-2007 AIS.2004.09
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Pennsylvania Peace Links Records
1978-2007
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Pennsylvania Peace Links
AIS.2004.09
29.04 Linear Feet (26 boxes)
Pennsylvania Peace Links was founded in 1983 and was a chapter of a national organization committed to the prevention of nuclear war through peaceful alternatives by promoting educational programs, citizen diplomacy and conflict management. Materials in the collection include correspondence, volunteer and contributor lists, programs, flyers, news clippings, audio-visual material, and brochures.
History
Peace Links was a national organization committed to promoting peaceful alternatives to nuclear war. Betty Bumpers, wife of former U.S. Senator Dale Bumpers, founded the organization in Little Rock, Arkansas in 1982. The Pennsylvania Peace Links chapter was established in Pittsburgh on July 6, 1983 by a group of influential local women, including Teresa Heinz and Joan Specter. Mary J. Paradise served as the first president. Other founding officers of Pennsylvania Peace Links were Toni Conaway, Teresa Wilson, Ruth Friedman, Mary Sheehan, and June Stool. The organization collaborated with other nuclear disarmament groups on various efforts, such as Physicians for Social Responsibility (in organizing the Concert for Peace in 1984), the Nurse Alliance for the Prevention of Nuclear War, and the Union of Concerned Scientists. After the end of the Cold War, Peace Links remained dedicated to the abolishment of nuclear weapons, but their mission also widened to include women's rights and equitable development worldwide. Peace Links was recognized as an accredited Non-Governmental Organization (NGO) by the United Nations, and a delegation from Pennsylvania Peace Links attended the United Nations Fourth World Conference on Women in Beijing, China on September 4-15, 1995. The national office in Washington DC closed in the summer of 2001, with subsequent disbandment of the Pennsylvania chapter in 2007 and the North Carolina chapter in 2011.
Scope and Content Notes
This collection consists of the records of Pennsylvania Peace Links, spanning the years 1981-2004. Activities of local chapters and various members are represented along with major outreach projects such as workshops, panels, concerts and educational programs. Documentation includes the Peace Links' attendance at the United Nation's Fourth World Conference on Women and records generated from the organization's involvement in other international conferences pertaining to women's rights issues. Additional materials have been added under new sections located at the end of each series entitled, "New Material Added, 2011."
Arrangement
Additional scope notes are found at the series level. The records are divided into eleven series:
Series I. Administrative and Organizational Records,1983-2000
Series II. Subject and Outreach Records, 1981-2007
Series III. Outreach Evaluation Records, 1983-2003
Series IV. Peace Links Guides, 1985-1999
Series V. Concert for Peace, 1983-1984
Series VI. Nuclear Weapons, 1978-2004
Series VII. Pittsburgh/Beijing and Beyond, 1985-2000
Series VIII. Soviet Women's Visits, 1985-1994
Series IX. Photographs, 1983-2003
Series X. Audio-Visual Material, 1980-2000
Series XI. Related Organizations, 1983-1999
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Accruals
Additional records were received by the ASC from the Pennsylvania Peace Links organization, via Executive Director Janice Auth, on May 17, 2004 and August 2004, and from former president Mary J. Paradise in March 2005. Subsequent materials were received from Dr. Jack Paradise, the husband of the late Mary Paradise, in 2009.
Acquisition Information
The original collection was received as a gift from Pennsylvania Peace Links by the Special Collections Department, University of Pittsburgh, 1997. These records were transferred to the Archives Service Center on January 20, 2004.
Previous Citation
Pennsylvania Peace Links Records, 1981-2004, AIS.2004.09, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
Related Material
Physicians for Social Responsibility, Pittsburgh, Pa. Records, 1971-2004, AIS.2005.02, Archives & Special Collections, University of Pittsburgh Library System
Pittsburgh Peace Institute Records, 1984-1997, AIS.1998.01, Archives & Special Collections, University of Pittsburgh Library System
Thomas Merton Center Records, 1971-2004, AIS.1982.19, Archives & Special Collections, University of Pittsburgh Library System
The University of Arkansas holds the Peace Links National Records in their Special Collections (MC907 and MC907a).
Additional related material can be found in an anthology of stories and reflections by participants of the Pittsburgh/Beijing and Beyond '95 project entitled To Beijing and Beyond: Pittsburgh and the United Nations Fourth World Conference on Women, edited by Janice Auth.
Separated Material
Published materials from the collection have been incorporated into the University of Pittsburgh Library System.
Social action -- Pennsylvania; Women and peace -- Societies, etc.; Feminism -- Pennsylvania; Women -- Pennsylvania -- Societies and clubs; Women -- Social conditions -- Congresses; Women -- International cooperation -- Congresses; Women and peace -- Congresses; Peace movements -- Pennsylvania; Pennsylvania Peace Links
- Administrative and Organizational Records, 1983-2000; I.
  Scope and Content Notes
  This series contains reports from Pennsylvania Peace Links to the national Peace Links office, member directories, minutes from the Board of Directors and Executive Committee, and other organizational records. A large part of the series contains records from various chapters that were established throughout the region as subsidiaries of Pennsylvania Peace Links. New materials were added June 2011 in the section entitled, "New Material Added, 2011".
  - Board of Directors Minutes, 1983-1999 (Box 1, Folder 1-16)
  - Executive Committee Minutes, 1985-1989 (Box 1, Folder 17-21)
  - Executive Committee Minutes, 1993-1995 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Annual Reports, 1983-1988 (Box 1, Folder 23-27)
  - Annual Reports, 1994-1995 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Running Reports, 1985-86 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Reports – Board, 1986 – 87 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Reports – FY, 1987 – 1988 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Monthly Reports – To National, undated (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Brown, Carl (Attorney), undated (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Board of Directors, Members, undated (Box 1, Folder 34-36)
  - Organizational Structure – State level, undated (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Core Group Materials, undated (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Organizational Materials, undated (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Organizational Meeting, July 6, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Handbooks, undated (Box 1, Folder 41-42)
  - Directories, undated (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Post Kickoff, undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - New Members, undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Charter/By-Laws, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Background/Promotion, Mission, undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Mission and Goals, undated (Box 2, Folder 5-7)
  - National Board and Office, undated (Box 2, Folder 8-11)
  - National Board-Annette Remsburg, undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - National Board Meetings, 1987-1990 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - National Conference, June 23-24, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - National Meeting, 1985, 1990, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 15-17)
  - Finance Committee, undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Local Reports, Western Pennsylvania, 1984-1985 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Peace Links meeting, Mott House, March 2, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Chapter Sample – Steering Committee, undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Chapter Kickoff events, undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Potential Chapters, undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - New Chapter Materials, undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Altoona – Hollidaysburg Chapter, undated (Box 2, Folder 25-26)
  - Beaver County Chapter, undated (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Beaver Falls Chapter, Beth Miller, undated (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Center Region Chapter, undated (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Chambersburg Chapter, undated (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Danville – Bloomsburg Chapter, undated (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Delaware County Chapter, undated (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Edinboro Chapter, undated (Box 2, Folder 33-34)
  - Freeport Chapter, undated (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Indiana County Chapter information, undated (Box 2, Folder 36-37)
  - Morgantown Chapter (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Oil City Chapter, undated (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Pigeon Creek Presbyterian (Washington Co.) Chapter, undated (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - State College Chapter, undated (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Susquehanna Chapter, undated (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Peace People – Susquehanna Valley Chapter, undated (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Washington, Pa., Chapter, undated (Box 2, Folder 1-3)
  - New Material Added, 2011
    - Board Minutes, 1983 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Board Minutes, 1984 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Board Minutes, 1985 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Board Minutes, 1986 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Board Minutes, 1987 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Board Minutes, 1988 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Board Minutes, 1989 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Board Minutes, 1999-2000 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Board Reports, 1986-1987 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Bylaws, 1985 (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - Contributors, 1987 (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - Ephemera of Chapters, 1983-1987 (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - Fiscal year reports accomplishments, 1989-1991 (Box 20, Folder 13)
    - General Correspondence, 1983-1985 (Box 20, Folder 14)
    - History / Summary Print-outs, 1983-1987 (Box 20, Folder 15)
    - Legislations Correspondence, 1983-1988 (Box 20, Folder 16)
    - Local / State "Links", 1983-1984 (Box 20, Folder 17)
    - Mission Statement, 1987 (Box 20, Folder 18)
    - National Correspondence with Washington Peace Links, 1983-1987 (Box 20, Folder 19)
    - Organizing state-wide Peace Links events, 1983-1991 (Box 20, Folder 20)
    - Peace Links Later Administrative and Event file, 1998-2000 (Box 20, Folder 21)
    - Pennsylvania Organizational Executive Board, 1985-1989 (Box 20, Folder 22)
    - Sample Letters, 1983-1986 (Box 20, Folder 23)
    - Allentown Chapter, 1983-1985 (Box 20, Folder 24)
    - Butler Chapter, 1983-1984 (Box 20, Folder 25)
    - Carlisle Chapter, 1985 (Box 20, Folder 26)
    - Germantown, YMCA Chapters, undated (Box 20, Folder 27)
    - Harrisburg Chapters, 1984-1985 (Box 20, Folder 28)
    - Mercer Chapter, 1983-1989 (Box 20, Folder 29)
    - Ohio Peacelinks Chapter, 1985 (Box 20, Folder 30)
    - Philadelphia Chapter, 1983-1989 (Box 20, Folder 31)
    - Wheeling, West Virginia Chapter, 1985-1988 (Box 20, Folder 32)
    - Williamsport Chapter, 1984-1986 (Box 20, Folder 33)
    - Westmoreland Chapter, 1984-1989 (Box 20, Folder 34)
    - York Chapter, 1985-1988 (Box 20, Folder 35)
    - Map of Other Pennsylvania Chapters, Undated (Map-case 9-3)
- Subject and Outreach Records, 1981-2007; 1981-2000; II.
  This series details the breadth of issues, events, and activities in which the members of Peace Links were involved. Documents include records of conferences, trips, media and fundraising events, and other programs and projects. Particularly well represented material includes items on visits to China, conflict resolution youth programs, the Aaron Levinson audio-visual library, Soviet Union-United States cooperation, Peace Day, and the Sadako Project, which was an effort to memorialize victims of the atomic bomb in Hiroshima. Oversized documents relating to the Sadako project are housed separately in box 26. The office also kept alphabetically arranged files containing research and biographical information about people and events that were significant to Peace Links' mission. The papers of Mary J. Paradise and other founding members are part of these files. Materials include reports, pamphlets, bulletins, newsletters, newspaper clippings, and brochures. New materials were added June 2011 in the section entitled, "New Material Added, 2011".
  - ACWF/NGO Conference, March 1995 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Advisory Board, undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Art Project-Chautauqua at Pitt, October-November 1989 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Dr. Oscar Arias, Speech, November 1997 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Audio Visual Policy, July 1987 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Ruth Bayley Peace Award, 1989-1991 (Box 3, Folder 9-10)
  - Bayley, Ruth, undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Bedell, Elinor, undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Bibliographies, 1982-1990 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Breakfast Series, August 1990 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Bumpers, Betty, undated (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Bumpers/Elders Breakfast, October 1991 (Box 3, Folder 16-17)
  - Candidates Questionnaire, July 1992 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Chautauqua Trips, 1986-1991 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - 5th Annual Chautauqua Conference on US-Soviet Relations, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Chautauqua Trips, 1992-1994 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Children of War, 1986-1990 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - China Visits, 1993-2000 (Box 3, Folder 23-25)
  - All-China Women's Delegation, 1996-1997 (Box 3, Folder 26-27)
  - China Correspondence, 1989-1993 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Chinese Embassy-Washington, D.C., undated (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Chinese Children's Literature, undated (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Chinese Women's Association for Science and Technology, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Chittister, Sister Joan, undated (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Committee for National Security, 1985-1990 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Comprehensive Test Ban Meetings, 1993-1995 (Box 3, Folder 34-35)
  - Conaway, Toni, undated (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Conflict Resolution for Young Children, undated (Box 3, Folder 37-38)
  - Contacts, undated (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Contacts – Statewide, undated (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Copyright Material, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Daw Aung San Suu Kyi, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - D.C. Lobbying, 1994-1995 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Earth Day and Environment, 1989-1994 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Edgar, Bob, undated (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Edgar, Merle, undated (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Education Committee, 1983-1987 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Education Committee, 1992-1994 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Exchanges, 1987-1988 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Film Authorization and Releases, 1985-1992 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Films, 1984-1990 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Film Project, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Flea Markets, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Former Yugoslavia Project, 1993-1994 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Funding- Advertising Program, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Funding- Corporate Sponsors, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Funding- Endorsers, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Funded Grants, 1987-1988 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Funded – Follow, 1988-1991 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Funding, 1988-1991 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Fundraising Committee, 1988-1991 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Fund Raising Ideas, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Fundraising Lists – Margee, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Fundraising Potential, 1982-1990 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Funding, 1986-1989 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Funding- Goldstein, Lois, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Gund Foundation, 1985-1987 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Funding- ICFP Solicitation, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Funding- Lafe, William, 1985-1987 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Funding- Levinson Appeals and Mailing List, 1982-1991 (Box 4, Folder 23-25)
  - Funding- Mobay, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Funding- National Fund Appeal, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Funding- Paradise Fundraiser, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Funding- Pittsburgh Bridge & Iron Grant, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Funding- Proposals Submitted, 1983-1988 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Fundraising Requests, 1987-1988 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Funding- Proposal Materials, 1985-1988 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Funding- Prospective Funders, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Funding- Wine and Cheese Fundraiser, 1988-1989 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Funding- Sample Proposals, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Global Interactions, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Grassroots Conference, undated (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Greater Pittsburgh Commission for Women, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Gun Control, 1993-1994 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Heinz, Teresa, 1985-1992 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Hillman, Elsie, 1985-1990 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Hiroshima, 1982-1986 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Hollander, Barb, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Imagine Peace, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Internships, Goodwill Industries, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Iran-Contra Scandal, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - J.C. Penney Award, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Job Descriptions, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Just Denied: Human Rights and the International Financial Institutions, undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Kaul, T.N., 1995 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Kickoff Luncheon, April 1983 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Kostmayer, Pamela, undated (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Lamm, Dottie, 1991-1994 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Lantern Project, 1988-1990 (Box 5, Folder 14-21)
  - Lantern Project: Hiroshima Day, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Lantern Project: Earth Day Copies, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Lauffer, Erika, 1984-1986 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Levinson, Aaron, 1985-1992 (Box 5, Folder 25-27)
  - Levinson Audio-Visual Library, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Library Projects, 1984-1988 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Liepold, Mary, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Literature requests, 1983-1986 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Lobbying - 501(c)(3), undated (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Lobbying Trip, D.C., 1994 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Logo/Letters, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Long-Range, undated (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Lown, Bernard/Louise, 1988-1991 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Luncheon Programs, 1985, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Magee and Peace Links Trips, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Mailing Lists and Labels, undated (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - McCarthy, John, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Mirgorodskaya, Marina, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - National Gender Balance Project USA, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - National Peace Links Proposal, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - National Peace Links - Japan and International Programs, 1997-1999 (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - Nevada Test Site, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - Organizations for Peace, 1984-1990 (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - Nurse Alliance for the Prevention of Nuclear War (NAPNW), 1982 (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Outreach: Target Organizations, 1984-1987 (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Outreach Committee Minutes, 1985-86 (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - Outreach (local) – Dorothy Hill, undated (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - Outreach – local and state, undated (Box 5, Folder 51-52)
  - Paradise, Mary J. Papers, undated (Box 5, Folder 53-54)
  - Paradise, Mary J: Correspondence, 1985-1997 (Box 6, Folder 1-4)
  - Paradise, Mary J: Calendars, 1983-1987 (Box 6, Folder 5-6)
  - Peace Banner Craft Project (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Peace Day, 1982, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 8-10)
  - Peace Park and Garden, 1995-1999 (Box 6, Folder 11-12)
  - Peace Park and Garden- Plans, Sculptures, Action Pending, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Peace Park and Garden- Jim Ferlo, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Peace Park and Garden- Harrisburg, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Peace Park and Garden- International Peace Fountain, 1994-1995 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Exchange Program, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - MiraMed-Magee Trip to Russia, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Peace Links Museum, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Peace Links Chronology, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Peace Links Promotional Material, 1994-1995 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Peace Links Scholarship Packet, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Peace Links United Nations, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Peace Links Miscellaneous, 1997-99 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Peace on Earth Gala, December 6, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Persian Gulf Crisis, 1990-1991 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Phonathon, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Pittsburgh Coalition to Prevent Nuclear War, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Press File, 1984-1990 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Press Releases, 1987-1988 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Proclamations, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Pro Peace, 1985-1986 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Rape as a War Crime, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Procedure Notebook, undated (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Program & Education Committee, 1988-1989 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Program Planning, 1993-1994 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Program Scheduling, 1986-1987 (Box 6, Folder 37-41)
  - Redlener, Irwin, undated (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - Ruffing, Eloise, undated (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - Rush, Molly, undated (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - Russian Affiliates (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - Russia Articles, 1990-2000 (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - Sadako Project- Sadako Story Cards and Pictures (oversized), undated (Box 26)
  - Sadako Project- Story in Chinese and English, undated (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Sadako Project- Sterrett School Cranes Project, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Sadako Project- Playhouse of Point Park College Production, 1998-1999 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Sadako Project- Thousand Paper Cranes Activity (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - South Hills Evening Programs, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Star Wars, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Ten Year History, 1983-1993 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Sagan, Carl et al., undated (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Schoener, Marilyn, undated (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Schofield, Janet, undated (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Scranton, Coral V., undated (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Shevelyova, Yekaterina, undated (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Solarz, Nina, undated (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Specter, Joan, undated (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Spock, Dr. Ben, undated (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Students, undated (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Thomas, Marjorie, undated (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Thornburgh, Ginny, undated (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Tree House Puppet Show- Workshops and Conflict Resolution Committee, 1991-1999 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Tree House Puppet Show- Workshops with Lois Lowry, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Tree House Puppet Show- Tree House Productions, 1995-1997 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - US Report to the United Nations on the Status of Women, 1985-1994 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - University of Pittsburgh's Informal Program-China Deluxe, undated (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - University of Pittsburgh International Fair, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Video Projects, 1985-1986 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Volunteers, undated (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Volunteer Recognition, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Warnke, May, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - War Toys, 1986-1992 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Webb, Terry, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Wilson, Theresa, 1984-1986 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Women for America for the World, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Women for a Meaningful Summit, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Women's Action for Nuclear Disarmament National Affiliation Guide, undated (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Women's Rights Publications, undated (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - Women's Vote Project, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - Wright, Robin, 1991-1995 (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - YWCA Series – brochure, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - New Material Added, 2011
    - Ben Spock Fundraiser, 1984 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Betty Bumpers, 1981-1999 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Budget, 1983-1991 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Comprehensive Test Ban Campaign, 1990-1991 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - The Communicator, 1986 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Congressional Record, 1985 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Financial Accounting, 1984-1988 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Fund Appeal, 1988-1989 (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Initiation of Historic Archives for Grassroots Peace Organizations, 1993-1994 (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - International Links, 1983 (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Long Range Planning - Pennsylvania Peace Links, 1988-1989 (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - Mailing Lists and Resources, undated (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - National Newsletters and Enclosures, 1986-1999 (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - Newsletter Taskforce, 1986-1991 (Box 21, Folder 14)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1983-1988 (Box 21, Folder 15)
    - Notes for unnamed talk material, 1984-1998 (Box 21, Folder 16)
    - Outreach Committee, 1984-1986 (Box 21, Folder 17)
    - Outreach Committee, 1987-1989 (Box 21, Folder 18)
    - Pamphlets, 1983-2007 (Box 21, Folder 19)